behindthesigngiveaway.com 2019-01-06

# KOA Privacy Policy | KOA Campgrounds

Kampgrounds of America, Inc. (“we” or “us”) respects the importance of the privacy of your Personal Information, which means information that identifies you personally, either alone or in combination with other information available to us. This Privacy Policy discloses privacy practices for information we collect at our campgrounds and on the website www.koa.com (the “Site”). It gives you notice regarding:

  1. Personal Information we collect, how we use it, and with whom we may share it
  2. Choices you may make regarding our use of your data
  3. Security procedures we use to protect your Personal Information from misuse
  4. How you can correct any inaccuracies in your Personal Information
  5. Security and retention of your Personal Information
  6. Links to other websites
  7. Changes to this Privacy Policy
  8. Country-specific requirements

By using, browsing, or accessing the Site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. Your visit to the Site and any dispute over privacy are subject to the Terms of Use, including limitations on damages and application of the law of the State of Montana, U.S.A. Use of this Site is strictly voluntary. **If you do not agree to the Privacy Policy and Terms of Use for the Site, you must immediately log off the Site and may not use it.**

#### Territories

We host the Site currently on servers located within the United States, but the locations of our servers may change from time-to-time, and your Personal Information may be stored on servers located within the United States, Canada, or in another country. Further, our franchisees may maintain individual websites in the country or territory they service.

Privacy requirements and treatment of Personal Information varies from country to country. To meet these requirements, we have included certain “Country-Specific Privacy Notices” as part of this Privacy Policy. You may locate the Country-Specific Privacy Notices at the end of this Privacy Policy.

BY SUBMITTING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO US, YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IN THE UNITED STATES OR IN ANY OTHER COUNTRY IN THE WORLD. IF YOU ARE SUBMITTING PERSONAL INFORMATION OF THIRD PARTIES TO US, YOU WARRANT AND REPRESENT YOU HAVE THEIR CONSENT TO PROVIDE THEIR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO US AND WILL HOLD US HARMLESS FROM AND AGAINST CLAIMS BY SUCH INDIVIDUALS RELATING TO OUR USE OF SUCH PERSONAL INFORMATION WITHIN THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY.

#### Information Collection, Use, and Sharing

We collect your computer’s Internet protocol (IP) address, which you necessarily disclose when you visit the Site so that our computer may send data (such as the web pages you request) to your computer. The Site utilizes “cookies,” which are anonymous, unique identifiers that web pages on the Site may use to store data on your computer or send data to our web server. We may use cookie data to “recognize” you when you visit the Site in the future, to troubleshoot how the Site operates, and for internal analysis of how people use the Site. Should you decide not to accept cookies from the Site, you will limit the functionality we can provide when you visit the Site.

We receive and may store Personal Information you enter on the Site or give to us in any other way, such as at a campground. For example, we collect information that you voluntarily give us by e-mail, by conducting business with us on this Site, or by registering on this Site or in person to camp at a KOA campground. If you choose to share any Personal Information with us, you will see that the amount and type of Personal Information required by us depends on the activity you are engaging in. For example, to reserve a campsite, you must provide contact information (such as name, address, and telephone number) and financial information (such as credit card number and expiration date). We use this information to bill you or to fulfill your reservation or other purchase. If we have trouble processing your reservation or other purchase, we will use this information to contact you.

We may use the Personal Information you provide for particular activities, including, without limitation, processing your reservation; processing your credit card payment; collections; customer service; marketing and research; providing services, product, promotional and other information to you with your consent; and to contact you regarding administrative notices. We may share this information with our franchisees and with marketing partners, advertisers, and other parties with whom we collaborate to provide specific services to you. When you sign up for certain services, we will share names, or other contact information necessary for the third party to fulfill your order or intent to obtain the service or services. For example, we must release your credit card information to credit card authorization service providers and our credit card-acquiring (merchant) bank to process your payment for purchases.

We may share Personal Information with our franchisees. We may rent this information to parties who promote the outdoor recreation and hospitality industry and related products and services, using means and practices we approve. We do not speak for our franchisees in this policy statement, because they independently own and operate their campgrounds. Likewise, we do not speak for third parties to whom we rent your Personal Information. While we attempt to be selective in working with such third parties, we are not responsible for their use of your Personal Information. Each franchisee’s and third party’s privacy policy will govern how that franchisee or third party uses and protects your Personal Information.

From time-to-time, we request information on the Site via surveys, sweepstakes, or contests. Participation in these surveys, sweepstakes, or contests is voluntary, and you may choose whether to participate and therefore disclose information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name, address, telephone number, e-mail address) and demographic information (such as zip code or age level). We use contact information to notify sweepstakes and contest winners and award prizes. We use survey information to monitor and improve the use and satisfaction of this Site and your camping experience at KOA campgrounds.

We do research on our users’ demographics, interests, and behavior based on the information provided to us during your use of the Site or our campgrounds and may aggregate the data collected. Aggregated data does not include Personal Information. We may share this aggregate information with vendors, potential advertisers, business partners, or other third parties.

We may disclose information in any of the following circumstances: (1) in response to a subpoena, search warrant, court order, or other legal process or request, or as may otherwise be required by applicable law or regulation; (2) to protect and defend our rights or property or those of its affiliates, dealers, business partners, or others; or (3) as we, in our sole discretion, believe is appropriate under exigent circumstances in response to a perceived threat to the personal safety, property, or rights of any person or organization. Since our database is a business asset, in the event we are reorganize or sell the business or agree to merge with another company, you consent to the sale, assignment, or transfer of your Personal Information to a purchaser of all or substantially all of our business assets, or to an affiliate, as applicable.

Unless you ask us not to, you consent to our contacting you via e-mail in the future to tell you about specials, new camping opportunities, new services, or changes to this Privacy Policy. We will never request your password, user name, credit card information or other personal information through e-mail.

#### Your Access to and Control of Information

You may [**opt out of any future communications from us**](https://email.koa.net/pub/sf/ResponseForm?_ri_=X0Gzc2X%3DYQpglLjHJlYQGzb1vLmrF4WSNzbyzbJzeIEDW6gNFWy7G1oczg9p03PqJf76DahUdVXMtX%3DYQpglLjHJlYQGnA5kYzd9j4kOzbfFCzbfFizeLNUzctAECvvPHhKPKm0tpPzgEfzb6r&_ei_=EpS7nXeDYt0VPG4gaFMBk5-bUK8gW-5HY_otGr0A7y9LyAlLh44I) at any time. You can do the following at any time by contacting us via the e-mail address or phone number given on our Site:

  * See what data we have about you, if any.
  * Change or correct any data we have about you.
  * Have us delete any data we have about you.
  * Express any concern you have about our use of your data.

We will respond to reasonable requests within the time limits established by applicable law or within a reasonable time if applicable law does not establish a time limit. For your protection, we may ask you for additional information to verify your identity. In most cases, we will provide the information you request and correct or delete any inaccurate Personal Information you discover. We reserve the right, however, to limit or deny your request, to the extent permitted by applicable law, if: (1) the disclosure may threaten the personal safety, property, or rights of any other person or organization; (2) the disclosure may lead to a violation of applicable laws or regulations; or (3) where you have failed to provide sufficient evidence to verify your identity.

#### Security

We take precautions to protect your information and the security of your information is important to us. We will comply with our credit card merchant banks’ requirements for the use and storage of your credit card information, such as obligations concerning the security of your credit card numbers, as well as any laws that apply to the use and storage of that information.

Although we cannot guarantee against loss, misuse, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or destruction of data, we use commercially reasonable security measures to protect you from such occurrences. You acknowledge that: (1) there are security and privacy limitations in computer systems and on the Internet which are beyond our control; (2) the security, integrity, and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through the Site cannot be guaranteed; and (3) any such information and data may be viewed or tampered with by a third party while such information or data is being used, transmitted, processed, or stored.

#### Retention of Your Personal Information

We keep your Personal Information only as long as we need it for the purposes for which it was originally collected (or to which you have subsequently consented) or for other legitimate purposes (such as regulatory compliance), or as permitted by applicable law.

#### Our Relationship to Other Sites That Can Be Accessed Through This Site

This Site may contain links to other websites. Additionally, other websites may contain links to this Site. We do not review or monitor the websites linked to this Site and is not responsible for the contents or privacy policies related to any other websites. If you visit one of these other websites, you may want to review the privacy policy on that website.

#### Changes to Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy, completely or in part, from time to time through the posting of notices on the Site, at any time and without notice to you, that this Privacy Policy has changed (“Notices”). You expressly waive any right to receive Notices. You should check the Site frequently for Notices to identify modifications of the Privacy Policy that may be of interest to you. Any use of the Site following the date on which we implement changes to this Privacy Policy or post a Notice constitutes your acceptance of all such changes.

If you have concerns about this Privacy Policy, you should contact us immediately via telephone at (406) 248-7444 or via e-mail at [questions@koa.net](mailto:questions@koa.net).

#### Country-Specific Privacy Notices

#### Canada

KOA complies with the Canadian Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (“PIPEDA”) and substantially similar provincial laws and regulations.

_Accountability._ We are responsible for your Personal Information under our control. We have appointed a Chief Privacy Officer who is accountable for our compliance with this Privacy Policy. Any inquiries should be directed to by mail addressed to Kampgrounds of America, Inc., Attn: Chief Privacy Officer, TWIII Building, 4th Floor, Billings, MT 59101 U.S.A., or by e-mail at [questions@koa.net](mailto:questions@koa.net).

_Purposes._ We collect Personal Information for the purposes listed above and we may share your Personal Information with the third parties listed above under the heading “Information Collection, Use, and Sharing.” We will post Notices outlining any new purpose for the use of your Personal Information. Your failure to object to such uses shall be deemed to be your consent to the use of your Personal Information for the new purposes so indicated. In the event we intend to use your Personal Information for a purpose unique to you, we will obtain your specific consent for the use of your Personal Information for that purpose.

_Consent._ When you access the Site or request services from us, whether directly or through our representatives, affiliates or franchisees, KOA will deem you to have consented to the use of your Personal Information for the purposes set forth above. In the event we wish to utilize your Personal Information for purposes unique to you, other than those listed above under the heading “Use of Your Personal Information,” we will obtain your consent as identified in the section entitled “Purposes” above.

_Disclosure and Retention._ We will collect and use your Personal Information only in the manner and for the uses set forth above in the section entitled “Purposes” and only for so long as may be set forth under the heading “Retention of Your Personal Information”.

_Accuracy._ We strive to maintain the accuracy and completeness of your Personal Information. You may ask us to correct information contained within our records. Request for correction must be made in writing to by mail at Kampgrounds of America, Inc., Attn: Chief Privacy Officer, TWIII Building, 4th Floor, Billings, MT 59101 U.S.A.

_Safeguards._ We take reasonable precautions to protect your Personal Information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction as set forth above in the under the heading “Security.”

_Individual Access._ Upon your request, we will disclose to you whether we have any of your Personal Information in our possession. Written requests should be direct to Kampgrounds of America, Inc., Attn: Chief Privacy Officer, TWIII Building, 4th Floor, Billings, MT 59101 U.S.A. We will provide you with a written response explaining the use of your Personal Information and the organizations to which we disclosed it. You may correct or amend any Personal Information if you believe it is inaccurate or incomplete. We specifically reserve the right to deny you access to your Personal Information if that would likely reveal personal information about a third party or otherwise are of the opinion that the disclosure of your Personal Information would be objectionable pursuant to Section 9 of PIPEDA. We will either provide you with access to your Personal Information or object to your access within thirty (30) days of our receipt of your request.

_Amendments to Our Privacy Policy._ We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time as set forth under the heading “Changes to Privacy Policy.” Complaints. If you have a complaint concerning our collection or use of your Personal Information, please contact the Kampgrounds of America, Inc., Attn: Chief Privacy Officer, TWIII Building, 4th Floor, Billings, MT 59101 U.S.A., or by e-mail at [questions@koa.net](mailto:questions@koa.net). We will attempt to respond to and resolve those complaints to your satisfaction.

Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) / Copyright Policy
